I've been thinking about it's a little
bit similar to when I was in my last
walking thought I guess we could call
these little things I'm doing about
meaning right and I think not
not meaning in the sense of this word
means this but more meaning in the sense
of meaningfulness sense of that which
grants or shows something to be
significant connected things that
connect like having a meaningful life
that kind of meeting and also about this
this strange the strange sense of
anonymity and meaning yeah I was
thinking about a story my dad told me a
while ago my dad's uh been sober for you
know like thirty five years or something
and and Alcoholics Anonymous and he's
really been active most of you know his
whole sobriety he sponsors people and he
speaks and it's been a big a really
hugely significant part of his life and
he's got he tells really funny he's
funny is funny stories he was saying one
time that he was at a like a conference
or convention like an AAA convention and
this guy runs up to him with this
expression of relief and gratitude and
he says oh my god I've been looking for
you for years but we lost touch and I
lost you numbered so I wasn't able to
like get a hold of you I'm so glad I ran
into you
and apparently this guy from years ago
they had a conversation or maybe my dad
was his sponsor or something and the guy
basically tells him he says like
something that my dad said right was
ended up being a life-changing thing for
this guy right it's like one of those
one of those moments of like Gregory
Bateson would say the difference that
makes the difference and he said it the
that this thing that my dad said was the
thing that changed his life for the
better and and it also because it
changed his life had changed his
family's life for the better his
community like one of these things like
a like a groundbreaking
epic thing and then they lost touch so
he could never tell him so this is this
moment got to actually thank him and
tell him it you know and then he got
done talking and they said goodbye my
dad says to himself he completely
misunderstood what I meant it's funny
I've always you know if all the stories
my dad says he's like you know he's a
storyteller like he's good at it but
there's certain ones that stick and this
is one of the ones that stick and I've
been thinking about it a lot lately it's
been kind of coming into my head
and I think the reason why is because it
it it points to it demonstrates
something there's something about this
story that demonstrates something right
that you know we could ask for example
we can we can ask well the thing that
the guy heard right what did he hear did
he hear what my dad said right if he
didn't what did he hear if did he hear
himself
this misunderstanding was it the thing
did it realize my dad's intentions and
saying it even though he misunderstood
it and I think it was obvious in the
sense of like of course it be
wouldn't it be it could be almost occur
kind of mean if my dad went hey listen
what I really meant was so there's it's
really interesting it's kind of like if
we look at that well what was the true
meaning of wisdom was was the meaning
lie in my dad's intentions did it lie in
his words did it lie in the man's
hearing who was who actually spoke the
thing that was in some sense accountable
or made the difference that changed this
man's life for the better and I was
thinking about that nicest thinking
about like I think that this highlights
this strange sense of a very very deep
if we could say almost like a spiritual
anonymity in some way right like you
just get this sense of and I think
that's probably the case like more than
if we think about it this anonymity or
this dynamic of anonymity
perhaps operates underneath things and
the movement of the unfolding of the
world in so many ways I think maybe
another way to get at it is to think
about the ground the structure of these
houses this neighborhood who the houses
were built by the many generations that
in some level still show in the
background and the way these houses
house in this neighborhood neighborhoods
how it gathers the sense of its being
right in these people in some sense are
disclosed in their anonymity or another
way to get at this is if you think about
it you know you've probably heard the
expression of you ask yourself you
probably know your grandfather's name
but do you know his grandfather's name
or his great-grandfather's name but even
if you have to go further back at some
point you're probably gonna you're gonna
hit the point in which you don't know
yet on some level the characteristics of
the way that you talk and the implicit
meaningfulness of your body language
your accent your way of walking your
gait these things that are so much of
you that they're so close that you could
probably even barely even see them
objectively or it would take a lot of
work to be able to see it objectively
there you are of them yet the source of
these things it's it lives in its
anonymity maybe even in its difficulty
for you to see because it's so close
and I guess there's a way in which this
you know there's a sense right now you
know I'm not thinking about anybody in
particular but just a general sense of
the way sometimes hear people talk about
the world right and there's a
understandably so there's a lot of
people talking about like oh we have got
we got we have to got to figure out the
world and lots of theories about what
the world is and what's wrong with it
and how to address it and everything we
were throwing seems like almost
everybody's thinking about that
however if if kind of like the thing
that made the difference with my dad's
friend whatever it was that granted the
significance of what he heard whoever
did that was anonymous
it seems kind of strange on some level
to think to grant too much seriousness
and my intentions or my conscious
intentions as attached to the self that
I conceived of myself as having that
there may be some a be a lot more
mysterious than that maybe the world the
world is not the kind of thing that I
can I can profit eyes in the sense of
making it some object that I can then
solve and then again even if I do that
where we all do that I'm sure we'll find
out something at the end of the day like
my dad found out
so what is that what is it to become
intimate with that sense right that
sense of mystery that sense of mystery
in its closeness mystery and it's in the
way that that on some level what I am
the relationships in which I am
constituted of can move can disclose
themselves in in its hiddenness so how
is it that it seems like if that is
something like we're a very deep sense
of meaning or being right comes from it
seems like whatever that is getting
close to that
seems to be a hint and what it is to be